# Curriculum Vitae

Rebecca Smethurst

September 11, 2017

University of Nottingham University Park NG7 2RD United Kingdom

Email: rebecca.smethurst@nottingham.ac.uk

Web: rebeccasmethurst.co.uk Phone: (+44) 0115 846 8819

I am the Ogden Trust Sixty Symbols research fellow at the University of Nottingham Astronomy department working with MaNGA data. My research interests include galaxy morphology, quenching, star formation histories and black holes. I am also an enthusiastic science communicator and I regularly present science interest videos on the Sixty Symbols YouTube channel.

## Research Experience

January 2017 -

Sixty Symbols Research Fellow University of Nottingham

October 2013 - January 2017:

DPhil Project: The influence of morphology, AGN and environment on the quenching histories of galaxies.

Supervisor: Chris Lintott University of Oxford

October 2011 - June 2012:

MPhys Project: Searching for TP-AGB star signatures in post-starburst ('E+A') galaxies: Are high redshift galaxy masses over estimated?

Supervisors: Russell J. Smith, John Lucey

**Durham University** 

## Observing Experience

February 2015:

Observer at the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii

November 2014:

Remote observer, from Oxford, with the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii

Observer at the INT Spectrograph in La Palma, Canary Islands

#### Achievements & Awards

IoP Early Career Physics Communicators Award 2015

Finalist

FameLab UK National Final April 2014

Audience Winner and Judges Runner-Up

Parent's Association Prize for Leadership September 2008

Bolton School Girls' Division

Prize for Achievement in Physics September 2008

Bolton School Girls' Division

#### First Author Papers

SDSS-IV MaNGA: Slow Rotators Quench Faster than Fast Rotators

Smethurst, R. J.; Masters, K. L.; Lintott, C. J.; Weijmans, A.; Merrifield, M.; Penny, S. J.; Aragón-Salamanca, A.; Brownstein, J.; Bundy, K.; Drory, N.; Law, D. R.; Nichol, R. C. Submitted to MNRAS (August 2017)

Supermassive Black Holes in Disk-Dominated Galaxies Outgrow their Bulges and Co-Evolve with their Host Galaxies

MNRAS, 470, 1559 (2017)

Simmons, B. D.; Smethurst, R. J. & Lintott, C. J.

Galaxy Zoo: The interplay of quenching mechanisms in the group environment

MNRAS, 469, 3670 (2017)

Smethurst, R. J.; Lintott, C. J.; Bamford, S. P.; Hart, R. E.; Kruk, S. J.; Masters, K. L.; Nichol, R. C.; Simmons, B. D.

Galaxy Zoo: evidence for rapid, recent quenching within a population of AGN host galaxies MNRAS, 463, 2986 (2016)

Smethurst, R. J.; Lintott, C. J.; Simmons, B. D.; Schawinski, K.; Bamford, S. P.; Cardamone, C. N.; Kruk, S. J.; Masters, K. L.; Urry, C. M.; Willett, K. W.; Wong, O. I.

Galaxy Zoo: Evidence for Diverse Star Formation Histories through the Green Valley MNRAS, 450, 435 (2015)

Smethurst, R. J.; Lintott, C. J.; Simmons, B. D.; Schawinski, K.; Marshall, P. J.; Bamford, S.; Fortson, L.; Kaviraj, S.; Masters, K. L.; Melvin, T.; Nichol, R. C.; Skibba, R. A.; Willett, K. W.

#### Education

October 2013 - January 2017: DPhil, Pembroke College, University of Oxford

Supervisor: Professor Chris Lintott

October 2008 - June 2012: MPhys, St. Aidan's College, University of Durham

1st class MPhys degree in Physics and Astronomy

September 1998 - August 2008: Bolton School Girls' Division

A-Levels: Physics (A), Maths (A), Further Maths (A), Chemistry (A), General Studies (A)

#### Teaching Experience

January 2014 - present:

Undergraduate Laboratory Demonstrator: University of Oxford

### Positions of Responsibilty

November 2014 - present:

Pembroke College, Oxford, MCR Secretary

June 2014 - November 2014:

Pembroke College, Oxford, MCR Social Secretary

June 2011 - June 2012:

St. Aidan's College, Durham, JCR Secretary

June 2010 - June 2011:

St. Aidan's College, Durham, JCR Social Chair